## **Pramith Prakash,**

## Senior Interactive Developer

Pavani Sarovar, Nallurahalli Rd, Nallurahalli, Whitefield, Bengaluru,

Email: pramithprakash@gmail.com

Mobile: 09663393036

### **Summary**

Senior Interactive Developer in Sapient's Bangalore office. Since Joining Sapient in November 2013, he has participated in the design and development which used technologies like ReactJS, AngularJS, LESS/SASS, RequireJS, OOP JS, jQuery, Git, bitbucket etc. Total around nine years of experience in UI Development.

Knowledge of technologies including **AngularJs-1**, **ReactJS-16**, ES6, npm, XHTML, Html5, CSS, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, SASS, LESS, RequireJs, GruntJs, (basic Angular2-4 knowledge) and Creative tools like Photoshop, Zeplin, Sketch etc.

### **Work Experience**

### Sapient Corporation, November 2014 to present

Senior Interactive Developer L2- Helios [Nissan, Infiniti, Renault, Datsun, Dacia]

The digital experience is at the heart of the relationship between the brands and their customers. With Helios project, Nissan and Renault–Nissan Alliance aims to offer internet users with the best technology for their online interaction with the different Alliance brands, be it through a computer, a mobile phone or a tablet. The ambition of Helios is to create a single 'best in class' global digital platform for all brands in the Renault-Nissan Alliance and deploy it for every region and market globally. Helios will eventually serve 170 digital sites for Nissan Motor Corporation 100 markets worldwide

Front End development - small team management, Handlebar framework, JS, Jasmine test cases for unit testcases, Estimating the front work.

Skills/Domain: Front End Development, jQuery, JavaScript, RequireJs, Handlebar, npm, ReactJS, ES6, webpack

#### Senior Interactive Developer - MGM

The MGM Grand Las Vegas is a hotel casino located on the Las Vegas Strip in Paradise, Nevada. The MGM Grand is the second largest hotel in the world by number of rooms and the largest hotel resort complex in the United States, ahead of The Venetian. Also done the html/Interactive for MGM Resorts Mobile App.

- Used AngularJS framework, RequieJS and GruntJS / npm tools for validating and compressing javascripts.
- Used LESS framework for writing CSS. SVG, PictureFill for images etc
- Responsive layout.

Place : Bangalore Pramith Prakash

## **Pramith Prakash,**

## Senior Interactive Developer

Email: <a href="mailto:pramithprakash@gmail.com">pramithprakash@gmail.com</a>

Mobile: 09663393036

Interactive Developer - TR.COM Design and Implementation

TR.com is a leading trading company and the purpose of the project was to develop a ecommerce website.

- Used SASS framework for writing CSS.
- Used BoilerPlate Design pathern, RequieJS and GruntJS tools for validating and compressing javascripts.
- Wrote a custom stylish select-box jQuery plugin.

## ISPG Technologies PVT LTD, December 2010 to November 2013

Lead UI Developer – Conversion on the Design templates to Interactive, Responsive User Interfaces (HTML files) compatible for Desktop, Mobile and Tablet. Design integration for Deal Website (oorjit – A Product of ISPG Technologies), E-Commerce Web Products like Pinnacle Cart and other open source frameworks.

The aim of projects done is to make compatible with all the standard Digital Medias.

- Involved in requirements analysis and effort estimation for the project
- Was part of the product development
- Conversion of Design Template to Interactive XHTML Pages
- Developed a Advanced Html Editor tool with all standard tools like Drag and Drop, Editing contents instantly, Styling html contents
- Testing XHTML pages on various browsers and mobile devices including Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, Opera, and Internet Explorer.
- Developing Valid XHTML and CSS with the help for Web Development tools like Firebug, Web Development Toolbar, and Internet Explore Developer Toolbar.

## UI Developer - Web Applications

- Developed XHTML pages compatible for mobile and tablet devices
- Developed a Text Editor for a Iphone mobile app
- Was responsible for User Interface as a UI Developer
- Testing the pages on various browsers and mobile devices
- Developing Valid W3C standard XHTML and CSS

## Srishti Software Applications PVT LTD, November 2009 to December 2010

Web Developer – Developing Web Content Management and Web Publishing Systems with the help of Valid XHTML and CSS, Design Integration, Reusing existing design templates with few design changes

- Converting Design templates to XHTML pages
- Enforce User Interface style consistency across components
- Developing Valid XHTML and CSS
- Optimizing the web pages

Place: Bangalore Pramith Prakash

## **Pramith Prakash,**

# Senior Interactive Developer

Email: <a href="mailto:pramithprakash@gmail.com">pramithprakash@gmail.com</a>

Mobile: 09663393036

Was part of the three-member client-site team

Fixed the UI bugs and compatible issues

### Education

Kannur University, Kerala, India

Bachelor of Computer Application, 2009

#### Skills

Operating Systems Mac, Windows

Programming Languages and

Scripting

ReactJS, AngularJS, XHTML, CSS/CSS3, JavaScript,

**JQuery** 

Applications Vscode, Sublime, Atom, Sketch, Photoshop and other

designing tools

### Certifications/Training

- ReactJS certification from stack-route (9-week training done from Sapient)
- 3days Angular2-4 training done.
- Developing Web applications through Rich Internet Application tools like CSS and JavaScript
- Renault-Nissan | Apollo Awards Q4 2017, 2018

#### Strength

Strong problem solving and logical thinking abilities. Ability to learn new tools, technologies fast, Browser Compatibility

I hereby declare that all the above information furnished by me is accurate to the best of my knowledge. I assure I will put in the best of my efforts and strive hard for the benefit of the organization.

Github – Website –

https://github.com/hellopramith http://pramith.com/

https://github.com/pramithprakash http://pramithprakash.com/

https://in.linkedin.com/in/pramith-prakash

Place: Bangalore Pramith Prakash